Guide to the Archives of Irish America County Societies Collection AIA.003
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Archives of Irish America County Societies Collection
1906-2007
AIA.003
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
15.0 linear feet (18 boxes, including 1 oversize and one card box)
The collection consists of printed materials such as circular letters, dinner journals, program flyers and other printed ephemera related to the activities of Irish-American county societies based in New York City. Series are arranged by county name. Some files include minutes, correspondence, financial papers and photographs of functions (for photographs, see series XXV, Roscommon).
Archives of Irish America.
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists primarily of printed materials such as circular letters, dinner journals and flyers related to the activities of Irish county societies based in New York City,dating mostly from the twentieth century. Dinner-dances, balls and events in conjunction with St. Patrick's Day, and activities of hurling and Gaelic football clubs are extensively documented in the collection.
All of the series contain journals and programs from dances and banquets. Of special note in the collection are Series XI: Fermanagh, XV: Kilkenny, and Series XXV: Roscommon. In addition to programs and journals, these series also contain financial records, correspondence, membership logs and information, and minutes. Photographs of social events, most unidentified, can be found in the Clare, Fermanagh and Roscommon series. Series XXVI: Sligo contains a published history of the County Sligo assocation in New York. Series VI: Cork contains a County Cork Flag filed with an obituary in remembrance of Dr. Maire Bradshaw, sister of the Mayor of Limerick and a Ph.D. in zoology and botany. Dr. Bradshaw held the position of Assistant Director of Scientific Research for the Helena Rubenstein Comsmetics Corporation in New York and later worked for New York City's Department of Health in the Bureau of Radiation Control.
Note to the researcher: At present the collection does not include material for every county,but a series for each county was created in anticipation of future acquisitions.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in 32 series, listed alphabetically by county name. Files are arranged alphabetically within each series.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Provenance
Material in this collection was acquired from individual officers and members of particular county societies, was collected by archives staff, or came to the Archives as part of a larger collection.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Archives of Irish America Vertical File Collection (AIA 013) Gaelic Athletic Association (AIA 028) Ancient Order of Hibernians (AIA 046) United Irish Counties Association of New York (AIA 056) Emerald Societies of New York (AIA 057)
Historical/Biographical Note
Irish county organizations were first organized in New York City in the late 1840s. The early societies were for the most part purely social organizations, but in the 1870s some of them started to offer benefits for sickness and death. Sports teams (especially hurling and Gaelic football clubs) were to become an important component of county organizations. In the 1880s, inspired by the land reform movement in Ireland, many additional county societies were organized. Evictions and high rents were often fought on a local basis in Ireland, and in New York a county society rather than one of the broader Irish fraternal or social organizations seemed the best vehicle for responding to sudden developments in the old country. In the early 1890s the first attempt was made to establish a central body to coordinate the Irish county societies; such an organization was set up in Manhattan and at the same time a similar coordinating body was formed in Brooklyn, where many county societies existed independently. Both of these overseeing bodies were similar in design to the present-day United Irish Counties Association (UICA), but after only a few years of work the early umbrella organizations went out of existence.
A very detailed and informative history of county societies in New York by John T. Ridge, Mary McMullan and Mae O'Driscoll(from which the text above was excerpted and adapted)can be found on the UICA web site, at:
http://www.uicany.org/United_Irish_Counties/History.html
Gilroy, John G.; Black-and-white photographs.; Clippings (information artifacts).; Correspondence.; Financial records.; Gaelic football.; Hurling (Game); Irish Americans |x Social life and customs.; Irish |z United States |x Societies; Ledgers (account books).; Minutes.; Souvenir programs.
- I. Antrim
- II. Armagh, 1979-2003
  - County Armagh Assocation of New York Inc., Anniversary Celebration, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - County Armagh Assocation of New York Inc., Anniversary Celebration / Victory Celebration Dance, 1999, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - County Armagh Assocation of New York Inc., Annual Dinner Dance, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - County Armagh Assocation of New York Inc., Armagh Ball, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - County Armagh Assocation of New York Inc., Tomas O Fiaich Memorial Fund, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - County Armagh Donnelly Family Benefit Fund, circa 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - County Armagh Men's P&B Assocation of New York Dinner-Dance, 1979, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- III. Carlow, 1907-1999
  - Carlow Assocation of New York: Correspondence, 1957, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - County Carlow Assocation of New York Annual Dinner-Dance, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - County Carlow Men's Society Annual Ball, 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - County Carlow Men's Social and Benevolent Association Minutes, Jan 1908-Jan 1918 (Box 2a, Folder 1)
- IV. Cavan, 1979-2005
  - Gaelic Football and Social Club of New York Annual Dinner-Dance, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Gaelic Football and Social Club of New York Annual Dinner-Dance, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Gaelic Football and Social Club of New York Annual Dinner-Dance, 1998, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - P&B Assocation Inc. Annual St. Patrick's Dinner-Dance, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - P&B Assocation Inc. Annual St. Patrick's Dinner-Dance, 1989, 1992, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - P&B Assocation Inc. Annual St. Patrick's Dinner-Dance, 2000, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - P&B Assocation Inc. 150th Anniversary, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - West Cavan Reunion Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- V. Clare, 1945-1999
  - Assocation of Chicago Silver Anniversiary Dinner-Dance, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Dalcassian Scoial and Athletic Club Annual Dinner-Dance, 1977-1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Football Club Annual Dinner-Dance, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hurling Club of New York Annual Dinner-Dance, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Hurling Club of New York Annual Dinner-Dance, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hurling Club of New York Annual Dinner-Dance, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hurling Club of New York Annual Dinner-Dance, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hurling Club of New York Annual Dinner-Dance, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Senior Hurling Club Field Day and Games, Aug 11, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - International Tour, Dinner-Dance and Receptoin for the Clare Senior Hulring Team and Officials, Oct 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Annual Ball, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Annual Ball, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Annual Ball, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Annual Ball, Miscellaneous Materials, 1983-1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Annual Dinner-Dance Journals, 1945-1955 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Annual Dinner-Dance Journals, 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Annual Dinner-Dance Journals, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Annual Dinner-Dance Journals, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Annual Dinner-Dance Journals, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Annual Dinner-Dance Journals, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Annual Dinner-Dance Journals, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Centennial Banquet Committee, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Centennial Banquet Ads, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Centennial Banquet Ticket Sales, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Centennial Banquet Ticket Sales Check copies and notes, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Centennial Banquet Journal Ads, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Centennial Commemorative Book COmmittee, 1983-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Centennial Banquet Journal Adds, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Centennial Banquet Journal Adds, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Centennial Year Celebration, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Clippings, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Constitution and By-laws, 1966, 1983, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Correspondence, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Correspondence, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Darling Girl from Clare Festival, 1987-1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Installation of Officers, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Lovely Rose of Clare Pageant, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Mailing List, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Member's Dues Books, 1956-1985 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Property [Office inventory](Trustee Report), 1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Special Events, 1968, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Stationery, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Claremens and Womens' Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: Annual Dinner-Dance Journals, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Claremens and Womens' Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association of New York City, Inc.: The Banner, 1963 (Box 2a, Folder 2)
  - Miltown Malbay Social Club of New York City, Inc., 1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Lists and Ephemera, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Photographs: 100th Anniversary Ball, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 22a)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 22b)
- VI. Cork, 1959-2007
  - Cork Benevolent, Patriotic and Protective Assocation, 2005, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Corkmen's Benevolent, Patriotic and Protective Assocation Annual Ball, 1959, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Corkmen's Benevolent, Patriotic and Protective Assocation Centennial Celebration Program, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Corkmen's Benevolent, Patriotic and Protective Assocation Correspondence, 1984-1990, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Corkmen's Benevolent, Patriotic and Protective Assocation St. Patrick's Celebration Dinner-Dance, 1978, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Corkmen's Benevolent, Patriotic and Protective Assocation St. Patrick's Day Banquet, 1989, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Corkmen's Benevolent, Patriotic and Protective Assocation St. Patrick's Day Banquet, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Flag: County Cork Flag and Obituary in remembrance of Dr. Maire Bradshaw, undated (Box 4a)
- VII. Derry, 1972-1989
  - Derry Society of New York Annual Bloody Sunday Memorial Mass, Jan 30, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Derry Society Memorial March and Mass for Derry Thirteen, Feb 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Derry Society of New York Testimonial Dinner, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- VIII. Donegal, 1992-1996
  - Donegal Association of New York, Inc. Irish Soldier Memorials, 1992, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Donegal Footbal Club of New York 46th Anniversary Gala Banquet, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- IX. Down
- X. Dublin, 1977-1990
  - Dublin Society of New York Annual Dinner-Dance, 1984, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dublin Society of New York Annual Dinner-Dance, 1987, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dublin Society of New York Annual St. Patrick's Day Dinner-Dance, 1977, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- XI. Fermanagh, 1903-2001
  - Annual Dinner-Dances, 1977-1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Annual Dinner-Dances, 1988-1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Ball of the Mens and Ladies Associations, Feb 1919 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, May 1903 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1931-1985 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Director John G. Gilroy, 1978-1998, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Fermanagh Gaelic Football Commemorative Journal, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Literature about Fermanagh, 1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1977-1996 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Members and Mailing Lists, 1990-2000 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - New York Irish History Roundtable article, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Notes - Director John G. Gilroy, 1992, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - St. Mary's Pipe Band, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - St. Patrick's Day Parades, 1986-1995 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Souvenir Journal Advertising, 1985-1997 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Photographs, 1989, 1996, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Digital media (floppy disk, unlabeled), undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
- XII. Galway, 1932-2006
  - Galway Association of New York, Inc. 125th Anniversary Celebration and Banquet, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Galway Association of New York, Inc. Annual St. Patrick's Day Dinner-Dance, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Galway Association of New York, Inc. Annual St. Patrick's Day Dinner-Dance, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Galway Association of New York, Inc. Annual St. Patrick's Day Dinner-Dance, 2002, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Galway Association of New York, Inc. Remembrance of Colonel Patrick Kelly, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Galway Cathedral Fund Gala Benefit Ball (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Combined Galway Club of New York Testimonial Dinner: Galway Champion Football Team of 1956, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Galway Golf Society: 1st Galway Memorial Golf Outing, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Hurling Club of New York Irish Tour, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Hurling Club of New York Dinner Dance Programs, 1972, 1980, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Hurling Club of New York Dinner Dance Journals, 1985, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Hurling Club Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 10a)
  - Men's Association Annual Banquet, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Men's Association Centennial Address: Cardinal Cook, Oct 24, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Men's Asscoiation Attendance Book, 1971-1995 (Box 5a, Folder 1)
  - Men's Association Membership Ledger, 1950s-1980s (Box 5a, Folder 2)
  - Men's Association Minute Book, Jul 1916-Dec 1926 (Box 5a, Folder 3)
  - Men's Association Minute Book, Jan 1927-1928 (Box 5a, Folder 4)
  - Men's Association Minute Book, 1933-1951 (Box 5a, Folder 5)
  - Men's Association Minute Book, 1951-1957 (Box 5a, Folder 6)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association Annual Ball, 1966-1970 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association Annual Ball, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association Annual Ball; Bicentennial Dinner Dance, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association Auditor's Report, Jan 1, 1957-Apr 30, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association Centennial Celebration and Banquet, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association Letterhead/Stationery, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1942-1957 (Box 5)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance Centennial, 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance Split Club, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Men's Social and Benevolent Association Testimonial Dinner, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Micael Moran J. R. A. Club St. Patrick's Night Galway Ball, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- XIII. Kerry, 1959-1997
  - John Farrel Testimonial Dinner, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Gaelic Football Club of New York Annual Dinner Dance, 1991-1995 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Gaelic Football Club of New York Annual Dinner Dance, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Kerrymen's Patriotic and Benevolent Association All-Ireland Football Champion Banquet, 1959, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Kerrymen's Patriotic and Benevolent Association Annual Dinner Dance, 1984, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Kerrymen's Patriotic and Benevolent Association, 1994, 1997, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
- XIV. Kildare
- XV. Kilkenny Kilkenny Men's Social and Benevolent Association, 1906-1993
  - Allied Irish Bank: Corporate Resolution, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Allied Irish Bank: Statements, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Allied Irish Bank: Statements, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Allied Irish Bank: Statements, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Allied Irish Bank: Statements, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Annual Ball and Dinner-Dance: Correspondence and Circulars, 1975-1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Annual Ball and Dinner Dance Programs, 1973-1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Annual Dinner Dance Tickets, 1974-1977, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bills and Expenses, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cash Book, 1977-1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1986 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Diamond Jubilee Banquet, April 29, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Dinner Dance Finances, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Dinner and Formal Rough Sheets, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Gaelic Athletic Association, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Golden Jubilee Banquet, Oct 31, 9153 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Hurling Club of New York, 1974-1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Incorporation Documents, 1903, 1906-1954, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Internal Revenue Service (IRS) Audit, 1973-1978 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Ledger Book, 1978-1980 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Mialing Address Lists and Mailings to Members, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Membership Cards; Information on Members, 1980-1987 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Membership Dues Ledger (photocopy), 1965-1976 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Memorial Society; Plot Improvement Fund, 1976-1984 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Minutes (photocopies of ledger book pages), 1970-1975 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Newsletters, 1959-1965 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters and Announcements, 1976-1979 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Public Speeches and Statements, 1974-1984 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Receipts and Expenses, 1969-1976 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Receipts and Expenses, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Receipts and Expenses, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Receipts and Expenses, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Receipts and Expenses, 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Union Dime Savings Bank: Statements, 1970-1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- XVI. Laois/Leix, 1973-1976
  - Leix Gaelic Football and Hurling Club Annual Dinner Dance, 1973, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- XVII. Leitrim, 1915-2001
  - 101st Annual St. Patrick's Celebration Journal, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 102nd Annual St. Patrick's Celebration Journal, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 103rd Annual St. Patrick's Celebration Journal, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 105th Annual St. Patrick's Celebration, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Carrick-on-Shannon Co. Leitrim Historical Society Famine Memorial Drawing, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - County Leitrim Society Annual Ball, Grand Ball, Lotteries, 1965-1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - County Leitrim Society Centennial Year, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - County Leitrim Society Centennial Year Dinner Dance Program, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - County Leitrim Society of New York Correspondence, 1984, 1990-1999 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Leitrim Young Men's Patriotic, Benevolent and Social Association Ball/Benefit Social, 1915, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- XVIII. Limerick, 1990-1999
  - Hurling Club of New York Victory Celebration Dance, 1995, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Men's Benevolent and Social Assocation, Inc.: Centennial Ball, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- XIX. Longford, 1989-2006
  - Annual Dinner Dance Program, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Centennial Dinner Dance, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - County Longford Association / Social Club of New York St. Patrick's Dinner Dance, 1989-1992 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - County Longford Assocation St. Patrick's Day Dinner Dance, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - County Longford Assocation St. Patrick's Day Dinner Dance, 2003-2004 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- XX. Louth, 1956-2001
  - County Louth Society of New York, Inc: Annual Ball, 1996-2001 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - County Louth Society of New York, Inc.: Golden Jubilee Banquet, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- XXI. Mayo, 1924-2006
  - Erris Association of America, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Mayo Football Club of New York Annual Reunion and Dance, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 5)